MANUEL ACOSTA

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

	manuacostaok@gmail.com
--	------------------------

(+54) 11 6502 8141

San Miguel, Bs As, Arg.

ABOUT ME

I am a 28-year-old Full Stack Developer from Argentina. Passionate about software development, I consider myself a person who can achieve any goal I set, accomplishing objectives step by step. I began my IT journey in 2018 at the National University of General Sarmiento (UNGS) in San Miguel, where I learned about Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) with Java and Python, Testing, Software Specification and Engineering, and Project Management (Jira). In my free time, I decided to delve deeper into web development through various courses. Later, I participated in the state project "Argentina Programa," which allowed me to apply this knowledge in a Full Stack application project with Angular, which served as my portfolio for a while. It was there that I discovered my love for front-end development and decided to create a simpler portfolio with React. Recently, I developed an Android application in Kotlin that records entries and exits using facial recognition, as part of the culmination of my career as a Systems Technician.

EDUCATION

Universidad Nacional General Sarmiento

Graduated in Systems Technology.

2018 - 2024

Bachelor's Degree in Systems.

2018 - Present.

SKILLS

- Web Development Advanced (React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap)
- Java Advanced (OOP, SpringBoot, Hibernate)
- Databases (Psql, MySQL, PHP, MongoDB)
- Angular Intermediate (TypeScript)
- Python Intermediate
 (OpenCV, Google ML Kit)
- Kotlin Intermediate
- Git Intermediate
- Testing (Postman, Selenium, JUnit)
- UX/UI (Figma, Draw.io, XML)
- Jira Intermediate

LANGUAGES

- Español (NATIVO)
- Inglés (Intermedio)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Insurance Sales Agent

ABC Seguros -Nov 2014 - Nov 2016

Insurance Sales Agent for home, auto, and personal policies in a call center, with commissions and targets.

- Development of soft skills such as communication, teamwork, and public speaking.
- Development of sales skills.

PC and Mobile Technician

Station Games - 2017-2021

Customer service in sales of various technology devices, including gaming and appliances. PC assembly and repair, both software and hardware, diagnostics, cleanings. Solid knowledge in PC assembly and repair - Networks - Software: Operating System Installation - Troubleshooting Windows environment - Printer connection. Cell phone repair - Hardware (Modules, charging pins, boards, buttons) Software (Firmware repair)

- I expanded my knowledge in computer repair, which I did throughout my adolescence.
- I put into practice my knowledge of cell phone repair and expanded my client base.

Junior Full Stack Web Developer

Web Course - 2022 a 2023

We worked with a client using the agile Scrum methodology, tasked with developing a Full Stack app using modern technologies. Frontend development was done in Angular and React.js, backend in Java with Spring Boot, utilizing JWT for authentication, and deploying on Firebase for frontend and Render for backend.

• Experience in both front-end and back-end.

PORTFOLIO:

You can access my portfolio at the following link to view all my projects and skills in more detail, where you will also find my LinkedIn and GitHub profiles.

